"Please God, don't let him get caught."
Straight Time is a crime, drama film directed by Ulu Grosbard.
After being released on parole, a burglar attempts to go
straight, get a regular job, and just go by the rules.
He soon finds himself back in jail at the hands
of a power-hungry parole officer.
Max Dembo, played by Dustin Hoffman.
Jenny Mercer, played by Theresa Russell.
Willy Darin, played by Gary Busey.
Jerry Schue, played by Harry Dean Stanton.
Earl Frank, played by M. Emmet Walsh.
Carol Schue, played by Rita Taggart.
Straight Time is a 1978 American neo-noir crime drama film directed by Ulu Grosbard and
starring Dustin Hoffman, Theresa Russell, Gary Busey, Harry Dean Stanton, M.
Emmet Walsh, and Kathy Bates.
Its plot follows a lifelong thief in Los Angeles who struggles to
assimilate in society after serving a six-year prison sentence.
The film is based on the novel No Beast So Fierce by
Edward Bunker, who also acts in the film.
In addition to starring, Hoffman was originally hired as the film's director,
but was replaced by Grosbard after completing a day of shooting.
Principal photography took place in California in 1977, with shooting occurring in
Los Angeles, Sacramento, and several locations in the Inland Empire.
Warner Bros.
released Straight Time on March 17, 1978.
The film grossed $10 million at the United States box
office, and received largely favorable reviews.
In 2003, The New York Times placed the film on its
Best 1,000 Movies Ever Made list.
The film explores themes of prison, robbery,
police, murder, los angeles, california.
The tone is emotional.